Guide to the Bard Family Papers
Bard College Archives
- Johnston, Susannah (Bard) (1772-1845). Letter to her son, Francis U. Johnston, 1813
- Johnston, Susannah (Bard) (1772-1845) Letter to her son, Francis U. Johnston, 1813 - 1816
- Johnston, Susannah (Bard) (1772-1845) Letter to her son, Francis U. Johnston, June 24, 1816
- Johnston Susannah (Bard) (1772-1858) Letter to her son, Francis U. Johnston, July 18, 1816
- Johnston, Susannah (Bard)-(1772-1858) Letter to her son, Francis U. Johnston, February 5, 1817
- Johnston, Susannah (Bard) (1772-1845). Letter to her son, Francis U. Johnston, June 24, 1818
- Johnston, Susannah (Bard) (1772-1845). Letter to her son, Francis U. Johnston, September 24, 1818
- Johnston, Susannah (Bard) (1772-1845). Letter to her son, Francis U. Johnston, August 9, 1819
- Bard, Susannah. Letter to Mrs. Barton., April 7, 1820
- Bard, Samuel, 1742-1821. Letter to his grandson, Francis U. Johnston.
- Bard, Samuel, 1742-1821, Letter to his grandson, Francis U. Johnston., March 8, 1821
- Bard, Samuel, 1742-1821, Letter to his grandson, Francis U. Johnston., March 28, 1821
- Bard, Samuel, 1742-1821, Letter to his grandson, Francis U. Johnston., April 13, 1821
- Hobart, Letter to William Bard., May 2, 1832
- William Bard writes to his daughter, Susan., March 9, 1830
- Letter from Ferdinand Sands to Mr. William Bard., February 27, 1835
- DeNully, James. Letter to Caroline Bard, April 11, 1835
- Lieber, Francis. Letter to William Bard., July 11, 1835
- Sparks, Jared. Letter to William Bard., August 24, 1835
- Sparks, Jared. Letter to Mrs. Catherine (Cruger) Bard., November 2, 1838
- Winslow, K. S. Letter to William Bard. Enclosure., December 9, 1839
- Letter addressed to “Brother Joe” from Charles E. Sands and William Bard., January 18, 1845
- Bard, William. Letter to David Thompson., April 12, 1853
- Johnson, W. J. Letter to Mrs. Catherine (Cruger) Bard, November 16, 1853
- McVickar, John. Letter to John Bard., November 11, 1858
- Bishop Potter to John Bard. Day after the Chapel burned., December 28, 1858
- Pruyn, John V. L. Letter to John McVickar., August 16, 1859
- Potter, H. Letter to John Bard, August 22, 1859
- Letters from John V. L. Pruyn to John Bard., September 16, 1859 - 1859-09-31
- Letter to from John V. L. Pruyn to John Bard., January 28, 1860
- Letters to James Starr Clark (12 items), 1870 - 1873
- Letter to James Clark from John Bard., March 27, 1873
- Personal Papers, 1783 - 1899
- A hymn to be sung by the Charity Scholars., October 11, 1783
- Bard, John. Diploma of the New York academy of Medicine, 1789
- Bard, John. Last will and testament., January 23, 1795
- Bard, Samuel. Biographical account of his father, John Bard., 1800
- Bard, William. License to practice law in the state of New York granted to William Bard., January 31, 1800
- Certificate of law to William Bard to practice in the Court of Common Pleas, called the Mayor’s in the city of New York., August 6, 1800
- Lewis Morgan, Esq. Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of New York. License to practice law in the Supreme Court of New York issued to William Bard., January 13, 1802
- Livingston, Edward, Esq. Mayor of the City of New York. License to William Bard to practice in the Court of Common Pleas, the Mayor’s court in the city of New York., 1803
- Wallace, Joshua M. Letter to Samuel Bard. 1816, April 9 Lindsly, Philip. Formal notification of honorary degree of Doctor of Laws Conferred on Samuel Bard., April 9, 1816
- Bard, Samuel. Last Will., February 11, 1818
- Bard, Samuel, Recording of last will., September 17, 1821
- Bard, William. Genealogical chart, 1892
- Lewis, Richard. List of Ferns, May 14, 1899
- Real Property and Legal Documents, 1698 - 1863
- Bonds and Indentures, 1743 - 1810
- Bard, Bennet. Bond to Dinah Bard. Transaction, September 13, 1742
- Bard, John and William Farquhar. Bond to Catharin Stoutenburgh., May 3, 1750
- Edwards, John. Bond to John Bard., June 3, 1751
- Bard, Bennet. Bond to Dinah Bard., July 1, 1751
- Bard, Peter. Bond to Philip Kearny., November 14, 1754
- Bard, John. Bond to Charles Williams., December 22, 1761
- Brua, Michael. Bond to John Bard., April 20, 1763
- Scott, John. Bond of obligation to John Bard., May 10, 1764
- Bard, John. Bond to Walter Franklin., March 26, 1766
- Lazier, Lucas. Bond to John Bard., December 7, 1767
- Armstrong, Abner. Bond to John Bard., December 7, 1767
- Gillet, Charles. Bond to Bard, John., November 22, 1771
- Bard, Samuel. Indenture to Mary Barclay and Leonard Lispinard regarding the will of Rev. Henry Barclay., July 22, 1785
- Bard, Samuel. Bond to John Taylor., August 6, 1790
- Bush, John. Bond to Samuel Bard., April 15, 1799
- Pratt, Joel. Bond to Samuel Bard., September 4, 1800
- Contracts, 1763 - 1819
- Bard, John. Contract with Lucus Lazeir to manage farm, “Hyde Park.”, May 1, 1763
- Bard, Samuel. Contract agreement with Collins & Co. for publishing the fifth edition of his Compendium of midwifery., 1819
- Disputes of Land and Inquiries about Land Purchases, 1700 - 1804
- Alexander. Copy of the minutes of a meeting of the Nine Partners of the Pauling Purchase., 1700 - 1749
- Articles of agreement concerning disputed land divided among three parties., June 15, 1738
- Statement of case and memorandum concerning boundary dispute between Michael…atten and Paulings Purchase., 1754
- Kelly, John. Statement concerning land purchased by Dr. John Bard, November 24, 1767
- Thallhimer, Peter. Request to Samuel or John Bard or John Johnson for information regarding potential purchase of a plot of forested land., January 11, 1802
- Witt, Samuel, town clerk. “Articles of venue” for sale of land at Hyde Park mortgaged by John and Lena Bush to Samuel Bard, May 10, 1804
- Land Deeds, 1698 - 1798
- Anckerop, Indyan Sachem. Deed of land in Ulster County to Jacomyntie Elting. Copy made 1769, November 13., October 12, 1698
- Fauconnier, Peter. Petition for letters of patent to, Lord Edward Viscount of Cornbury., 1704
- Lord Edward Viscount of Cornbury., 1704
- Beekman, C. Deed of land to de Forest., 1714
- Bard, Peter. Deeds of tracts of land in Burlington County, New Jersey to Robert Macdonald., January 9, 1730
- Wright, Jashua. Deed of land in Burlington County to Dinah Bard., April 15, 1735
- Kearny, Philip. Deed of land in Burlington County (NJ) (obtained from Bennett Bard by a fore-closed mortgage) to Peter Bard., December 7, 1752
- Scott, John Morin. Land to J. Bard. Unsigned, 1760
- Smith, Benjamin. Deed of land in Westchester to John Bard, June 7, 1763
- Bard, Samuel. Deed of land to John Bard., November 10, 1763
- Abstract of John Bard’s title to lands in Warwick in Orange County., March 17, 1767
- Pitcher, James. Deed of land to Bard, John. With signatures from: Peter and Elizabeth Valleau, Stout Margaret (represented by attorney John Bard)., April 14, 1768
- Bard, John. Deed of land in Dutchess County to Samuel Bard., February 20, 1770
- Smith, William. Deed of land in Warrenstown to John Bard and others., March 6, 1772
- James, Earl of Perth. Deed of one hundred acres of unlocated land in East New Jersey to Peter Bard, January 6, 1773
- Livingston, Peter Vanbrugh. Deed of land in Sussex County to John Bard., September 16, 1774
- Bard, John. Deed of land in Dutchess County to Samuel Bard., February 19, 1776
- Bard, John. Deed of land in Dutchess County to John Rice., May 22, 1776
- Bard, John; Bard, Susanna. Deed of land to John Rice., May 23, 1776
- Armstrong, Asael; Armstrong, Elizabeth. Deed of land in Dutchess County to John Bard., February 24, 1779
- Johnston, David. Deed of land in Dutchess County to John Bard., May 4, 1779
- Bard, John. Deed of land (Warwick’s) to Denning, William., January 10, 1783
- Halloch, John. Deed of land in Dutchess County to Samuel Bard., August 29, 1785
- Stout, Margaret. Land to Samuel Bard., June 20, 1786
- Cross, Amos. Deed of land in Clinton Town County (Hyde Park) to John Bard., February 25, 1790
- Taylor, John. Deed of land in Orange County to Samuel Bard., August 5, 1790
- Muirson, Mrs. Dinah Magdalen (Bard). Deed of tract of land at Hyde Park to Samuel Bard., March 24, 1798
- Land Leases, 1751 - 1813
- Bard, John. Lease of land in Dutchess County to John Edwards. Signed by John Edwards., June 3, 1751
- Bard, John. Lease of land in Dutchess County to John Edwards. Signed by John Bard., June 3, 1751
- Bard, John. Lease of land in Dutchess County to Michael Housinger., May 1, 1763
- Smith, Benjamin. Lease to Anne Delancey and others, including John Bard., June 8, 1763
- Bard, John. Lease of land and negro servants to Lucas Lazeire., October 8, 1764
- Bard, John. Lease of land to Abner Armstrong and Asahel Armstrong., December 7, 1767
- Bard, John. Lease of land in Dutchess County to Thomas Banker., December 7, 1767
- Bard, John. Lease of land in Dutchess County to Lucas Lazier, December 7, 1767
- Pitcher, James. Lease of land to Stout, Margaret. With signatures from: Peter and Elizabeth Valleau. John Bard. Susannah Bard., April 14, 1768
- Pitcher, James. Lease to Stout, Margaret. With signatures from: John Bard. Susannah Bard. Peter and Elizabeth Valleau., April 15, 1768
- Pitcher, John and others. Lease to John Bard and wife., April 15, 1768
- Bard, John. Advertisement of lands., May 12, 1768
- Bard, John. Lease of farm, Bell Vale, to Francis Baird., September 7, 1775
- Bard, John. Lease of land, Bell Vale, for six years to Francis Baird., December 21, 1775
- Bard, John. Lease of three tracts of land in Orange County to John Rice, December 23, 1784
- Stout, Margaret. Lease of release from Mrs. Stout to Samuel Bard for a lot in Clifton Park., June 20, 1786
- Smith, Thomas. Lease to Samuel Bard., July 27, 1790
- Smith, Thomas. Release for land in Orange County to Samuel Bard., July 28, 1790
- Gardner, Thomas. Lease of house in New York for four years to John Bard., January 30, 1793
- Roberstam, John. Lease to John Bard., January 6, 1791
- Bard, Samuel. Lease of land in Hyde Park patent to Ebenezer Stapler, January 1, 1810
- Lease of land in Dutchess County to Quock Quackenbush, January 1, 1811
- Bard, Samuel. Lease of land in Hyde Park to Quock Quackenbush, January 1, 1813
- Legal Matters, 1700 - 1853
- Bard, John. Accounts, etc. Various papers., 1700 - 1749
- Bard, John. Document granting power of attorney to Bard, Samuel. Witnessed by Peter Bard; John Valleau., November 26, 1767
- Culver, Jacob and others. Declaration of trust to John Bard., December 12, 1759
- Bard, John. Statement of settlement of financial affairs with his son, Samuel Bard., September 2, 1775
- Thomas, Helson. Quit claim to John Bard relating to the use and privilege of Fish Creek at Bard’s mill., March 18, 1779
- Bard, John. Articles of agreement between John Bard and Francis Baird, being the assignment of Dowdale’s lease of a forge., July 1, 1779
- Valleau, Fauconnier. Statement concerning patent from John Bard for two tracts of land., October 13, 1788
- Magniac, Hollingworth. Grant of power of Attorney to William Bard, August 16, 1844
- New York Life Insurance and Trust Company. Board of. Copy of a resolution concerning William Bard’s resignation from the office of actuary., April 15, 1853
- Maps, Land Surveys and Drafts, 1700 - 1786
- Fauconier. Map of Hyde Park, N.Y., 1700 - 1749
- Bard, Bennet. Draught of land belonging to Bennet Bard, 1700 - 1749
- Scattergood, Thomas. Surveyor’s draft and statement of land belonging to John Bard., February 20, 1720
- Scattergood, Thomas. Surveyor’s statement and draft of three islands in the Delaware River., April 10, 1723
- Alexander, Ja. Surveyor general’s survey of land in New Jersey belonging to Peter Bard., March 31, 1726
- DeWitt, John (?). Surveyor’s statement and draft concerning land belonging to John Bard in Charlotte precinct, Dutchess County., November 9, 1768
- DeWitt, John (?). Surveyor’s statement concerning land belonging to Bard, John., November 2, 1769
- Armstrong, John. Surveyor’s statement concerning land of Bard, John., March 29, 1773
- DeWitt, John. Survey and boundaries of land exchange between Armstrong, Asael and John Bard., January 6, 1779
- DeWitt, Simeon. Surveyor’s statement concerning a tract of John Bard’s land., February 11, 1786
- Mortgages of Land, 1766 - 1799
- Bard, John. Mortgage of land in Dutchess County to John Rice, November 29, 1766
- Stout, Margaret. Mortgage of Clifton Park to John Bard., September 29, 1768
- Stout, Margaret. Mortgage of Clifton Park to John Bard., September 30, 1768
- Chapman, Nathan. Mortgage of land in Ulster County to Bard, John., December 3, 1774
- Bard, John. Mortgage of land at Warwick to John Rice., December 24, 1784
- Pick, George. Mortgage to Samuel Bard., July 27, 1793
- Bard, John. Mortgage on Joseph de la Barre’s land in Orange County extended., April 8, 1793
- Bush, John. Mortgage of land in Dutchess County (Hyde Park) to Samuel Bard., June 10, 1799
- St. Stephens College, 1860 - 1863
- Seymour, George F. Secretary of the Board of Trustees of St. Stephen’s College. Letter to John Bard thanking him for the gift of $1,000 for the support of a professor (to last each year during his lifetime)., April 17, 1860
- Hopson George B. Warden at St. Stephen’s College. Letter to John Bard accepting appointment as Professor of Latin in St. Stephen’s College., October 17, 1863
- Images of the Family, 1638 - 1899
- Photographs, 1638 - 1899
- Painted Portraits, 1638 - 1899
- Bound Manuscripts Volumes, 1790
- Large manuscript book, 1, 1790
- Large manuscript book, 2, 1790
- Small manuscript book, 1, 1790
- Bound Prayer book, 1790